Hello friends, my name is Gaurav Singhvi
and I welcome you all to my channel
Blue Pecan Wealth Management.  So
friends, today we talk
about medical top-up plans or super top-up plans and
what are their features?
What are the specifications?  Should you
go for a Super Top-up plan?  How much sum
assured should you keep?  How much
premium can you pay for it?  Which
company's super top-up or top-up plan should you take
?  So let us know about all this in this video.
So friends, if you have
not subscribed to my channel then do it now
so that you will keep getting videos related to personal finance like this.
As
you know that medical insurance, health
insurance or mediclaim
is a very important factor in everyone's life and
taking mediclaim is also the most important aspect of financial planning.  There
is a requirement for everyone.  Whether it is a youngster, a married couple
with kids or someone in old age,
in case of accident, critical illness
or any existing disease,
everyone has to avail the hospitalization benefit.
So everyone needs mediclaim.
But not everyone has adequate
health insurance.  Why doesn't it happen
?  There is a common belief behind it
that whenever you take medical insurance,
you take medical insurance up to ₹3 lakh or ₹1 lakh or ₹1 lakh.
Before that, the
first reason is that you feel that you will
not fall ill or you do
not need much insurance.
Therefore, you take a cover of up to ₹3 lakh.
Second, if you compare the premiums,
you can get a policy with a cheaper premium.
Because you do
not want to pay a high premium for a policy of ₹101 or ₹25 lakh.  The
third reason could be that the person from whom you have
taken medical insurance, be it the
RM of the bank,
your LIC agent,
an executive of the policy market or your friend or
colleague, has
not told you in much detail about medical insurance.
That's why you take insurance up to ₹3 lakh or ₹5 lakh
or he also does
not want to tell you about a policy with higher premium.
Because
most people do not opt ​​for policies with higher sum assured.   We do all of these.  The
medical insurance
or health insurance that exists becomes very
inadequate.  And whenever
in case of hospitalization, especially
in case of critical illness or accident,
when the hospital bill comes for ₹20 to ₹25 lakh
and you have
health insurance of up to ₹3 lakh, then the
remaining amount has to be
met either by self-funding or you
borrow from someone or you have to
sell all your existing investments like stocks, mutual funds, bonds, FDs or bank savings accounts.  So
friends, to avoid this, you can take a super
top-up plan.  So let us see
in this video what is top-up plan?
What is Super Topup Plan?  And
what is the difference between these two?  So let me
tell you through an example
what is the difference between top-up and super top-up plans
?  Like there is a family in which there are two adults.  There is a
husband, wife and two children.
They take a base policy for two adults and two children up to ₹5 lakh
which can be taken from any of HDFC Ago,
ICICI LB Star Health Insurance Cigna or
Max BPA.
For example, two adults and two children are
a family.  He has a
₹5 lakh plan from HDFC Ago and has
taken a top-up plan of ₹1 lakh.  He has taken the top up plan
from IC LB.  Now
his claim comes to ₹1 lakh in that policy year.  So the
claim of ₹5 lakh will be settled by the first company
HDFC Bank and the remaining ₹5 lakh will be
settled by Lobert with ICICI.  But
in the same policy year, if any other family member gets any other
disease or there is an accidental case and
again a claim of ₹5 lakh is made there, then
in that case, the time period of any company as the first company has been
completed.  The base company which is
HDFC has already settled its issue
and the second company will not make the payment in that case
because the payment there has to go above a deductible limit.
So one drawback of top-up is
that they get the claim only once in a year
and that too only in the case when the
sum assured of the first company has been completed.  Now
we know what is Super Topup Plan
?  What happens in the Super Top Up plan is
that the same family has two adults plus two
children.  He has a base health insurance of ₹ lakh
from HDFC Ergo.
He has taken a top up plan of ₹1 lakh, Super
Top Up Plan, from ICC LB.
Now a claim of ₹1 lakh comes there.  So
first HDFC Argo will give ₹5 lakh.  After that, the remaining ₹5
lakh will be given as loan from IC
and after 6 months, if
any one of the family members again has an
accidental case or is hospitalized due to any disease, then the
remaining
₹5 lakh in this claim,
if you have taken a super top-up plan, then pay that loan from IC.
Therefore, friends, I would
like to give you such advice that whenever you
take any top-up or super top-up policy to
enhance your policy, to
increase the limit of your existing policy,
then you should choose super top-up planning.
Friends, why should you take Super Topup Plan
?  What is the reason behind this?  For example,
if you are single and have a
basic health cover of ₹1 lakh and
want to get a cover of ₹25 lakh, then this
insurance of ₹25 lakh will cost you
around ₹3 to ₹4,000.  Similarly, the
base policy for adults and true children costs
around ₹13,000 to ₹14,000.
Same if you increase your base policy by ₹25
lakh.  Ok?  So their
premium will be Rs 30 to 35,000.  And
if they do not want to spend ₹30 to ₹35,000
and want a cover of ₹25 lakh, then
they can also take a super top-up of ₹5 lakh over the base policy of ₹5 lakh.
So the premium for
super top-up for two adults and two children will be
roughly
between ₹6 to ₹7000 in all the companies.
So according to this, if your age is between 35 to 45
and you are husband, wife and two
children, if you have a base policy of
₹ lakh, then you can take a super topup of ₹ 20 lakh or 25 lakh for
between ₹ 5 to 7000.
This will increase your total sum assured from ₹20 lakh to ₹5
lakh and you will be
able to adequately cover all medical emergencies.  Friends, in this we
see
how you can add it to the health insurance as a
top-up, as an add-on, in the super top-up plan.
First of all, if
you have a base policy then you
can take a super top-up plan.  If you do
not have any base policy,
you can buy a policy by issuing a deductible of ₹ 1 lakh, 3 lakh, 5 lakh or 10 lakh.
Suppose I do not have any health
insurance policy and I have
fixed a deductible of ₹ lakh.  So first I will have to pay Rs 2 lakh
to the hospital as per my expenses.  After that, the
company will pay the super top-up for any claim that may arise.
Suppose if I get a claim of ₹1 lakh
then I have to pay it and if I get a
claim of ₹1 lakh then I will pay ₹1 lakh
and the remaining ₹8 lakh will be
paid by the Super Topup company.
Thirdly, which employees can avail this scheme are
corporate employees who have
medical cover from a corporate.  Group
insurance coverage continues.  All those
employees can take a super top-up plan.
Where their corporate gives coverage up to 5 lakh or ₹ lakh.
He can take the remaining coverage of ₹20 or ₹25 lakh from one of his super top up
plans to meet his medical emergencies
and get a good adequate
health insurance.  So friends,
you can take Super Top Up Plan from your existing
policy, suppose you have a base
policy of HDFC, ICCI or Star Health
Insurance, then you can also take Super Top Up Plan from the
same companies.  If you
have National, New India, Oriental or any
other government company.  If you have
basic health insurance, you
can take top-up from any private company.
There is no such rule that if
you have this base policy then you
cannot take top-up of any other policy.  You
can use super topup of any company.  Super Topup is a kind of extension.  There
is a kind of inner limit that
increases above your base limit.  This is counted as an
independent policy in a different way.
So friends, let us see
how claim settlement happens in this.
When I told you that you can get Super Topup
plans for ₹20 to ₹25 lakh for ₹000, ₹4000 or ₹6000.
So, obviously a question must be
coming in your mind
that if health insurance of ₹20 lakh
is available for only ₹5 or ₹6000, then will the company settle the claim
or when the claim comes, the company can
reject the claim due to some issue or the other. So
friends, let me tell you what is the
process of claim settlement, like
suppose you have a base policy of ₹5 lakh
and you have taken a super top-up of ₹1 lakh,
now your total sum assured is
₹15 lakh. Now here if a claim of ₹1 lakh
comes, then you have to first
inform the company. When you inform the first company,
take its reference and when that
limit of ₹5 lakh is completed, then
all the documents from the hospital
like admission report, doctor's
report, anesthesia report,
operation papers and all other
important factors, you have to
take the entire file from the hospital and submit it to them.  You will have to get it
verified and certified and
inform your super top up company.
Now in that case where the Super Topup
company is giving you the claim but that
hospital is not in the list of hospitals
or the hospital in which you are admitted is
not a network hospital of the
Super Topup company, then in that case
you will have to make the payment in cash
and later you
can get it as reimbursement.  So friends, I gave you
complete information about Super Topup or Topup.
Now I would
like to give you some more advice regarding medical and super topup.  You
all must have a good adequate medical or
health insurance.  If you have
a mediclaim like if I
talk about metros like Mumbai, Delhi, Bengaluru,
Hyderabad or Ahmedabad then you should have
a cover of ₹20 to ₹25 lakh.  If you
live in an urban area, you should have
insurance coverage up to ₹1 lakh.
And if you are in a small village or town
then there should be a coverage of ₹5 lakh.  But
basically, if you have a policy of Rs 1 lakh, 2 lakh or
3 lakh and you want to enhance it,
then you can increase your limit by utilizing super top-up.   The
second advice I would like to give you is that
you should never buy any policy from any online
platform or any online
executive.  Because
whenever you buy from an online executive,
his intention is
only to sell you the policy.
So they don't ask about your medical history.  Do
not ask about existing diseases.  They do
n't ask about your smoking and drinking habits.  If
you conceal any of these material facts and a
claim arises later, the insurance company may
refuse to pay the claim.  Whenever you
buy a health insurance, you should contact your
financial advisor or financial planner.
Met him.  Sat with them and
filled the forms.  Tell them about your entire
medical history or any pre-existing
diseases you have and after sitting with them and
consulting them, you can take a good
health insurance.  Friends, why do you need to
take Super Topup of Rs 20 lakh or 25 lakh or 50 lakh
?  Let me tell you
that if you look at the
top four or five multispecialty
hospitals in Ahmedabad, which are Selby Sterling Hospital, Apollo
or Judds Hospital or if we talk about Mumbai, then there is
Kokilaben Dhirubhai Ambani
Hospital, Beachfront Hospital, Bombay
Hospital, Lilavati Hospital or SL
Raija Hospital, all these hospitals, if
I talk about Delhi, then there is Apollo
Hospital, Fertis Hospital,
in all these hospitals the simple room rent is
between ₹5 to ₹7000, the ICU
charge is between ₹10,000.  Then
there are operation charges, anesthesia
charges, boarding charges, nursing
charges, specialist charges, super
specialist charges, and a
charge of ₹3000 to ₹4000 for each doctor's visit.
All these charges are so huge that they
cannot be covered in a normal policy of Rs 3 to 5 lakh.  That's why I have
this suggestion for you.  If you have a base
policy of Rs 3 to 5 lakh, then you should take a good
super top-up plan and protect your family
financially and medically.
Friends, if you have any query,
any concern, you want to know something else from me
about super topup or medical insurance, then you can ask me.
I have
made another video about medical insurance in which
I told what are the 10 factors on the
basis of which you can choose a good health
insurance.  If you have
not seen this video then you
can watch it by clicking on the i button.  So friends,
how did you like this video of mine?  You
must tell me.  If you liked this video of mine
, then like it.  Share it with your friends and
family.  Till then bye
, signing off.